## **Arpan**

## Goswami



#### Contact

#### **Address:**

101 P.K. Guha Road, Dum Dum Cantonment, Kolkata, India

Pincode: 700028

Phone:

+91 8697029343

**Email:** 

arpan.goswami21@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/coder-arpangoswami

## **Skills Highlights**

- Ruby on Rails
- React
- Ruby Scripting
- Javascript
- Redux
- REST API
- SQL
- Python
- MongoDb
- Angular

### **Certifications**

- React The Complete Guide (Udemy).
- LAMP Based Full-Stack Web Development (Ungineering).
- Design and Analysis of Algorithms(NPTEL).
- Programming Data Structures And Algorithms Using Python(NPTEL).

#### **About**

Experienced software developer with two and a half years of industry experience with keen interest in Full Stack web devlopment. My passion for programming, eagerness to learn and clear technical concepts make me good at problem solving and crafting forward-thinking solutions.

## **Work Experience**

# **Gemini Consulting and Services** (Jan 2024 - Present) **Projects:**

Full Stack Developer, Wiell Cornell Medicine (Jan 2024 - Present)

- Wrote scripts to make pre-matriculated students hide from the Global Address List and automatically unhide them when they are moved to matriculated on a particular trigger date.
- Developed the work flow TS and code for onboarding Burke Institute employees to our Identity Management system.
- Updated existing cronjob script to import 18k NYP contacts from their API to the Enterprise Directory.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Ruby scripting, LDAP.

#### Kreeti Technologies Pvt. Limited (Feb 2022 - Dec 2023) Projects:

Full Stack Developer, KUDO (Sep 2022 - Dec 2023)

- Implemented a dashboard for Application usage visualization across different type of meeting and interpreted languages used in them.
- Enhanced the API codebase by incorporating feature flags.
- Contributing to the development of comprehensive RFCs and making architectural and technical decisions.

**Technologies used:** Ruby on Rails, Rest API, Angular, ChartJS.

Data Migrations, Clockwork (Oct 2023 - Dec 2023)

- Writing scripts to fetch raw data from SQL and NoSQL databases and validating the data and discovering patterns.
- Resolving discrepancies that may arise during migration.

Technologies used: SQL, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails

Front End Devloper, JobAlley (Sep 2022 – Sep 2023)

- Creating features of job posting along with filtering and searching of jobs.
- Creating job pipeline feature which takes care of multiple hiring rounds consisting of MCQ, coding and interviews to the selected candidates.

Technologies used: React, Redux, Tailwind CSS, Javascript.

Full Stack Developer, Invoicing (Feb 2022 – Aug 2022)

- Built API endpoints for expense tracking and transaction acceptance/rejection cycle.
- Built responsive UI for user profile and transaction viewing and adding/updating sections.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, React, REST API, Javascript.

#### **Education**

**B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering** | (2018 - 2022) B.P.Poddar Institute Of Management and Technology | CGPA: 9.11